# **BEN MEIER**

♥ Dallas, TX **६** 608.620.4620

■ meier\_benjamin@outlook.com
Phttps://bennnyys.github.io/Ben-Meier/

## SUMMARY

A data scientist passionate about environmental and socioeconomic issues. I have 6 years of experience working with data to inform economic research and financial regulation. I look forward to new experiences that align with my passions.

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Information and Data Science, University of California, Berkeley

• GPA 4.0 of 4.0

### BS, Applied Math and Industrial Engineering, Iowa State University

**■ 2011 – 2016** 

• GPA 3.9 of 4.0

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming**: Python (pandas, numpy, scipy, scikit-learn, keras tensorflow, pytorch, beautiful soup), VBA, Stata, SAS, SQL, HTML, CSS, R (RStudio, tidyverse, ggplot2, dplyr, shiny)

**Data skills**: Cloud computing (AWS sagemaker, Google colab), Databases (SQL, SQL Server, SSIS), Anaconda, Git, VS Code, Visual Studio, Jira

**Visualization**: Tableau, Power BI, Python (matplotlib, seaborn, plotly)

**Methods**: Machine learning (clustering, K means, K nearest neighbors, decision trees, random forest, naive Bayes, neural networks), Statistics (logistic/linear regression, gradient descent)

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Exploratory Data Analysis of Los Angeles Traffic Collisions**

Course final project demonstrating experience with EDA and visualization in python (pandas, matplotlib, seaborn)

## **Clustering Analysis of Holding Companies**

• Self-directed project to identify clusters of financial institution in U.S. using public FR Y-9C data. Uses EDA, K-means and KNN clustering, and visualization in python (pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas

♥ Dallas, TX

Programmer Analyst II, Statistics

- Performed data migration and database design to on-board two new survey collections
- Developed dashboard for preliminary survey data to enable on-demand customer data access eliminating a 1-day lead time
- Developed four extract-transform-notify python automation jobs to eliminate over 700 hours of staff work per year
- Developed K-means clustering notebook and KNN clustering notebook to test proof of concept to pilot AWS Sagemaker environment
- Led requirements, development, testing, and deployment of five minor version software releases

#### Economic Research Assistant, Research

**≅** 2018 − 2019

- Developed R script to automate the retrieval, cleaning, and validation of data for economic modeling
- Developed VBA excel workbook to automatically update FOMC regional data

#### Business Operations Analyst, FRB Houston

**≅** 2016 − 2018

• Improved data collection and analysis of district cafeteria IRS de minimis calculation

## VOLUNTEER

- Coding mentorship....
- Sustainability Initiative (project manager for waste management, data analyst for calculating travel emissions)
- Eagle Scout

